lain Maitland

Fullstack Developer



About

13512 Gable Street

- Detroit Michigan MI 48212 US
- (737) 226-3943
- iainmaitland.com
- imaitland
- **y** iain_maitland

Web Development

Professional

React Rust Typescript Javascript NodeJS/Deno GraphQL

MySql/NoSql/Postgres

DevOps

Professional

AWS Docker Git

Languages

English (Native speaker)

Interests

Art

Photography Poetry Writing

Summary

lain hails from Manchester, England. He has a degree from the University of Cambridge, in Law and History of Art, and 5 years experience as a frontend and fullstack web developer. Before going freelance as a full stack developer he worked as an early employee for Steem, building user-facing apps and backend micro-services, with React, Typescript and NodeJS on their blockchain / social media platform as it scaled to 1M+ users. More recently using Rust, he has made a static site generator, while also working on an image hoster service and a networked key-value store (https://github.com/pingcap/talent-plan/tree/master/courses/rust). He is excited by any opportunity to use Rust's powerful features in production, particularly when it can complement his experience with Typescript, Javascript and React.

Experience

Freelance 05/2020 - Present

Develop useful software for a variety of clients Fullstack developer

Worked as a lead developer with a local and remote team of graphic and product designers to implement solutions for creative and b2b software briefs for a range of clients including General Motors, Amazon, Google and Ford.

- https://hobbes.work a portfolio site for an UI/UX studio using a modern Jamstack, a customized headless CMS and a React/Typescript frontend
- https://means.tv a media streaming platform with subscription features
- A custom CRM for General Motors in React and NodeJS used at Dealerships and special events nationwide

Steemit.com 03/2018 - 05/2020

Developed applications for the Steem blockchain Fullstack Developer

Worked as part of a remote agile team with 3 other developers, to develop and scale open source blockchain software (https://github.com/steemit) used by millions of users and processing millions of dollars in cryptocurrency transactions.

- Built the most popular frontend (React/Typescript) for the Steem blockchain, including authorization, market trading, and cryptocurrency wallet features
- https://steemit.com A reddit clone written in React, scaling from a few thousand to millions of users internationally
- https://signup.steemit.com/ User creation service or 'faucet,' onboarded more than a million new users
- https://wallet.steemit.com Feature-rich cryptocurrency wallet including trading, exchange and withdrawal

Quikly 05/2017 - 03/2018

Developed an administration dashboard in React Frontend Developer

Worked as lead React developer as part of an agile team on b2b dashboard software.

- Build out a GraphQL api in Ruby-on-rails to drive the react frontend
- Advocate for Typescript adoption within the company

Penske Media Corporation

01/2016 - 05/2017

Developed CMSs and frontends for magazines like rollingstone.com and variety.com Frontend Developer

Worked as part of an agile team with 2 other developers, developed CMS backends in Contentful, Wordpress and Drupal and frontends in React

Lead pivot from traditional CMS instances to a headless model

Education